Joel Poirier

FULL - STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Full Stack web developer backed with 4 years of experience in video production, marketing, team leadership, and customer service. Believe that every person has a story to tell and that technology allows for individuals to share those experiences together. Excited to bring a storytelling driven approach to web development and design.

PORTFOLIO: https://devjoelmichael.github.io/



619-569-6564



devjoelmichael@gmail.com



El Cajon, CA 92019



@devjoelmichael

Skills

// PROFESSIONAL

- Creative Thinking
- Responsive Design
- Conflict Resolution
- Teamwork
- Accountability
- Problem Solving
- Compassion
- Punctuality
- Goal setting
- Prioritization

// TECHNICAL

- JavaScript
- React
- HTML
- CSS/SCSS
- Rubv
- Ruby on Rails
- RSpec
- PostgreSQL
- Git
- Visual Studio Cod
- Atom
- Jest
- Canva
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Audition
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Davinci Resolve 15/16

Work Experience

FULL STACK - INTERN

ViziSites | Nov 2020 - Present

- Design and build customized websites for high end clientele using HTML,
 CSS, JavaScript, and WordPress.
- Collaborate on complex web designs to fulfill all the clients needs.
- Creating ways to make the user experience friendly, easy, and accessible.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

LEARN Academy | Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

- Designed and built a unique book lending App using React, Rails, JavaScript, HTML, and a mixture of CSS / SCSS
- Built a database designed to locate animals for park staff and visitors using PostgreSQL and Postman. Refined later using Ruby on Rails.
- Developed a text-based Sci-Fi adventure game using Ruby. Re-created for wider spread user operation using HTML, JavaScript, and CSS.
- Continued growth in communication skills by successfully navigating projects with other developers who all have different ways of communication and perspectives.

LEAD EDITOR / VIDEOGRAPHER

Homeward Film Co. | March 2016 – May 2020

- Wrote and Directed three short films that have been shown in theaters, festivals, and placed in competitions.
- Edited over 200 videos ranging from YouTube videos, personal and professional podcasts, short films, documentaries, and full-length feature films.
- Listened to countless customers describe their stories in great detail resulting in creative videos and screenplays.
- Wrote over 100 short stories for customers, business, and personal development.



https://github.com/devJoelMichael

Education

Film Production

Grossmont Community College 2010 - 2012

General Education

West Hills High School 2005 - 2009

SALES AND MARKETING MANAGER

Merry Maids | July 2014 – Jan 2016

- Created multiple company wide social media marketing campaigns for both elevating sales and gaining a diverse client base.
- Met with clients daily to evaluate their homes and provide the best service possible
 - for their individual needs.
- Established an atmosphere of compassion and teamwork in the staff

BARISTA / SHIFT LEAD

Starbucks | Aug 2010 – Mar 2016

- Anticipated and met between 150 to 300 customers' needs on a daily basis.
- Devoted years to the understanding the complexities of multiple regions beans and brewing processes
- Created countless custom orders to the standards of each customer.